Guide to the Hoover Institution Archives Photograph Card Catalog
Hoover Institution Archives
Hoover Institution Archives Photograph Card Catalog
1800-1992
Consult repository
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
The guide describes photographs separated from the paper materials of collections of personal or organizational papers organized by the archives until the practice of separating photographs from paper materials stopped in 1992. Paper materials for the collections may be described in a separate document under the same title.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
The guide describes photographs separated from the paper materials of collections of personal or organizational papers organized by the archives until the practice of separating photographs from paper materials stopped in 1992. Paper materials for the collections may be described in a separate document under the same title.
In order to view materials in the archives, please note the collection number and envelope or album letter code.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by collection title.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Genre
Photographs; Slides (Photographs); Drawings
Other Finding Aids
The information contained in this document is reformatted directly from the photograph card catalog in the Hoover Institution Archives reading room. Paper materials for the collections may be described in a separate document under the same title.
Separated Material
The photographs described in this document may have been separated from the paper materials of a collection of the same name. For more information on a particular collection, please contact the Hoover Institution Archives.
Container List
- Abenheim, Donald Collection, undated; 146 slides, 7 boxes (Box 85013 - Slide Cabinet)
  146 Slides of paintings, drawings and posters depicting various aspects of German history as well as German Uniforms.
- Abramson, Lillian Collection, circa 1939-1945; 225 prints, 3 envelopes (Box 83080 - 10.A-V Envelope A-B, mC)
  Photographs depicting activities of the U.S. Army Air Forces 31st Photographic Reconnaissance Squadron in England, France, and Germany during World War II.
- Adair, Fred L. Collection, undated; 88 photographs, 3 envelopes (Box 50009 - 10.A-V)
  - 81 photos of the staff and patients of a Red Cross hospital in Courtrai, Belgium, scenes of war damage in Belgium, and a French tank, undated (Box A-B)
  - 7 photos of Fred L. Adair and his colleagues, undated (Box mC)
    Includes Certificate. See map case
- Adenauer, Konrad Collection, 1945 and following; 15 prints, 1 envelope (Box 62006 - 10 A-V Envelope A)
  15 prints, including portraits and group shots.
- Adleman, Robert H. Collection, circa 1939-1945; 24 prints, 1 envelope (Folder 72075 - 8.12 Envelope A)
  24 prints dealing with the First Special Service Force (US and Canadian troops) and its operations in Italy and Southern France during World War II.
- Aid Refugee Chinese Intellectuals, Inc. (ARCI) Collection, undated; 715 prints, 6 envelopes (Box 70023 - 8.01)
  - 419 photographs removed from album entitled "ARCI-Hong Kong", undated (Folder A-D)
    Includes photos of staff, refugees, relocation facilities, and visitors such as Walter Judd and Ambassador Rankin. (see list of captions in accession folder)
  - 239 photographs removed from album entitled "To Dr. George A. Fitch, with Warm Bon Voyage Wishes from all the personnel of ARCI, Taipei.", undated (Box E)
    Includes photos of Walter Judd, Margaret Chase Smith, Everett Dirksen, Madame Chiang Kai-Shek. (see list of captions in accession folder)
  - 57 photographs removed from untitled album, undated (Box F)
    Includes photos of ARCI activities. (see list of captions in accession folder)
- Albrecht, (Ralph G.) Collection, 1945-1946; 115 prints / 1 photo album (Box 72025 - 8M.19 Album f)
  115 prints in a photo album during and after the negotiations at the Nuremberg war crime trials
- Alekseev, Mikhail V. Collection, 1968; 1975; 2 prints / 1 envelope (Box 77066 - 10,A-V: Envelope A)
  Two prints depicting Vera Alekseeva de Borel, daughter of General M.V. Alekseev, and her husband, Mikhail de Borel.
- Alexandra, Mother [Ileana, Princess of Romania] Collection, 1933-1937, undated; 243 prints and postcards / 8 envelopes (Box 78054 - 10.A-V)
  - 72 prints depicting King Ferdinand and Queen Marie of Romania and their children, before and right after World War I, including prints of King Alexander of Yugoslavia, husband of Princess Marie, as well as prints of the Duke and Duchess of Edinburgh, Queen Marie's parents (Folder A)
  - 28 prints depicting Princess Ileana of Romania, youngest daughter of King Ferdinand and Queen Marie; her husband Anton, Archduke of Austria and their children; her sisters and friends, as well as prints depicting Princess Ileana speaking in Munich for Radio Free Europe (with prints of the Iron Curtain) (Folder B)
  - 17 prints depicting Reverend Mother Abbess Alexandra, former Princess Ileana of Romania, Superioress of the Monastery of the Transfiguration in Ellwood City, Pennsylvania (Folder C)
  - 22 prints relating to the 1906 Exhibition in Bucharest commemorating 40 years of King Carol I reign; the 10 years festivities of Greater Romania in 1929; the coronation ceremony of King George VI and Queen Elisabeth of Great Britain in the Abbey of Westminster, May 12, 1937 (Box D)
  - 42 prints and postcards of the royal castles of Bran, Balcic (with prints of Queen Marie), and Sinaia; the Cotroceni Palace in Bucarest and the property of Copaceni (Box E)
  - 27 prints relating to Queen Marie's visit to Morocco in 1933 and 26 postcards of the turn of the century depicting Bucharest and Romanian countryside and folklore (Box F)
  - 1 print of Queen Elizabeth of Romania; 1 print of Laszlo's portrait of Queen Marie; 5 prints of Princess Helen and her son, King Michael (Folder mG)
  - 2 prints of Queen Marie (Folder mH)
- Alexandra, Queen, Consort of Edward VII, King of Great Britain Collection, 1844-1925; 1 album (Box 90059 - 8M.02 Album fA)
  Album entitled "Queen Alexandra's Christmas Gift Book: Photographs from My Camera", 1908, depicting King Edward VII of Great Britain and members of his family and entourage, and members of other royal families. Includes both original photographs and printed reproductions of photographs.
- Allen, Benjamin S. Collection, 1939-1939; 41 prints, 2 postcards/ 2 envelopes 2 photograph albums (Box 54001-10.A-V, 54001 - 8M.02)
  - 3 prints of Herbert Hoover, 1938; 6 prints of Herbert Hoover; 1 print of Ray Lyman Wilbur; 3 prints of Gunnison, Colorado, 1939; 1 print of Herbert Hoover, Benjamin Allen and others, Colorado 1939; 1 print of Herbert Hoover, Colfax, California, 1939; 1 print of Herbert Hoover, Benjamin Allen and others, 1938; 1 print of John Hallowell; 1 print of Edward Chambers; 1 print of Lou D. Sweet; 1 print of Raymond Pearl; 1 print of Theodore Whitmarsh; 1 print of Julius Barnes; 1 print of George Rolph; 2 prints of Herbert Hoover and others, Grass Valley, California, 1935; 1 print of Herbert Hoover and Charles Hebberd, Spokane, Washington, 1938; 1 print of Herbert Hoover and Otto Swangson; 1 print Herbert Hoover and others; 1 print of Herbert Hoover and others, San Francisco World's Fair, 1939; 3 prints of Herbert Hoover and others, Eugene, Oregon, 1939; 1 print of Herbert Hoover and unidentified man; 1 print of Herbert Hoover and Mrs. George B. Simmons; 2 prints of Herbert Hoover and others, Cebolla, California, 1939; 1 print of Herbert Hoover and others; 1 print of Judge Lindsay; 1 print of Tom Ellis; 1 print of the Conference of United States Food Administration; 1 unidentified print (Folder A)
  - 11 photographs of United States Food Administration posters (Folder B)
  - 1 album of prints of Herbert Hoover, U.S. Food Administration officials, food conservation photographs, and photographs of U.S. Food Administration posters, 1917-1919 (Folder fC)
  - 1 album of photographs of U.S. Food Administration posters and press releases, 1917-1919. (Folder fD)
- Allman, Norwood F. Collection, 1929-1987; 31 prints / 4 envelopes (Box 87042 - 10.A-V)
  - 12 prints of Norwood Allman alone and with others (Folder A)
  - 8 prints of the Norwood Allman and other members of the Shanghai Volunteer Corps (Folder B)
  - 7 prints of N. Allman and others on horseback and on foot at the Shanghai Race Course (Folder C)
  - 4 prints of N. Allman and others on horseback in the countryside (Box D)
- Alter, Arthur S. Collection, 1931; 1 print / 1 envelope (Box 79012 - 10.A-V Envelope Oversize)
  Mounted photograph of Adolf Hitler, taken on his birthday, and autographed by German national socialists
- Altrocchi (Rudolph) Collection, 1898-1899; 1910,; 1918-1919; 24 prints / 2 envelopes (Box 55001 - 8.20)
  - 16 photos of the staff of the American bureau of Public Information, Rome, Italy, 1918 and of military burials at Lyons, France, 1918-1919. 7 photos of other scenes including air flights at Campo de Marte in 1910, Queen Margherita of Italy in 1898 or 1899, and postcards (Folder A)
  - 1 photo of troops of the A.E.F. in military parade in France, 1919 (Folder mB)
- America First Committee Collection, undated; 20 prints / 2 envelopes (Box 42001 - 8.01/03)
  - 18 photographs of General Robert E. Wood, John T. Flynn, Alice Roosevelt Longworth, Charles A. Lindbergh, Sen. D. Worth Clark, Kathleen Norris, Lillian Gish, Cong. Karl E. Mundt, and American First Committee public displays, undated (Folder A)
  - 2 photos of A.F.C rallies at Los Angeles and Indianapolis, undated (Folder mB)
- American Library Association War Service Collection, 1917-1923; 1176 prints / 31 envelopes (Box 73025 - 10 A-V)
  - 580 photos of Libraries established by the American Library Association at U.S. military service camps. (List of camps and camp locations is available), circa 1918 (Folder A-J)
  - 6 photos of libraries established for Negro service men by the American Library Association at U.S. military service camps, circa 1918 (Box K)
  - 255 photos of libraries and library activities provided by the American Library Association at U.S. military and other hospitals. (List of hospitals is available), circa 1918 (Folder L-Q)
  - 47 photos of library and other activities for the blind, circa 1918-20 (Folder R)
  - 141 photos of libraries and library activities provided by the American Library Association at overseas military camps. (List of camp locations in available), circa 1918-1919 (Box 73025 - 10 A-V, Folder S-U)
  - 20 photos of library activities provided by the American Library Association on board military troop ships, 1918 (Folder V)
  - 11 photos of American Library Association War Service operations including photo of the headquarters at the Library of Congress, 1918 (Folder W)
  - 47 photos of book drives, displays, posters, etc. sponsored by the American Library Association and others to support library programs for service men (Folder X)
    Includes photo of artist Denman Kink.
  - 1 photo of a railroad car converted into a library by the Bolsheviks in Riga, Latvia to distribute communist literature, circa 1918 (Folder Z)
  - 21 photos of U.S. military forces in Hawaii, circa 1918 (Folder AA)
  - 6 photos of German prisoners of war, including a painting of prisoners of war by Louis Raemaker, circa 1919 (Folder BB)
  - 3 photos of World War I wartime scenes, including camouflaged woods near Verdun (Box 73025 - 10 A-V, Folder CC)
  - 19 photos of U.S. wartime production activities, including ship building and shell making (Folder DD)
  - 18 photos of U.S. military training, circa 1918 (Folder EE)
  - Photographs and postcards, depicting libraries provided for American soldiers in the U.S., France and Germany, during and immediately after World War I. Also includes general scenes of A.E.R. activities, 1917-1923 (Folder FF-GG)
- American Relief Administration Collection, 1920; 1 print (Box 23001 - map cabinet)
  1 print depicting the guests at the Invisible Guest Dinner, New York City.
- American Relief Administration. European Operations Collection, 1919-1923; Box No. 851-863 (Box 23001)
  See the register for description of photographs in this collection
- American Relief Administration. European Operations Collection, circa 1919-1923; 1 album (Box 23001 - 8.24)
  Photographs of staff members and relief operations of the American Relief Administration European Children's Fund in Vienna.
- American Relief Administration. Russian Unit Collection (Box 23003)
  See register for descriptions of photographs in this collection
- Anderson, Frederick L. Collection, 386 prints / 28 envelopes / 2 albums (in 1 box) (Box 75054 - 10.A-V)
  See register for list of photographs.
- Anderson, Ronald S. Collection, 1929-1980; 5 photo albums / 2 boxes (Box 86021 - 8M.02 Album fA-fB)
  5 albums of photographs depicting Japan before and after World War II
- Applegarth, John S. Collection, 1964; 75 prints / 2 envelopes / 9 negatives (Box 64011 - 8.20)
  - 75 photos of scenes of the 1964 riot in the Panama Canal Zone and of important persons involvled with the riot, including Victor M. Avila, President Roberto Chiari, Edwin M. Martin, and Cyrus R. Vance (Folder A)
  - 1 photo of a street scene of the 1964 riot in the Panama Canal Zone (Folder mB)
- Arachaa, Kara-Kys Dongikovna Collection, 1995; 19 color photographs / 1 envelope (Box 95006 - 10.A-V Envelope A)
  Depicts scenes of armed conflict in Chechnya.
- Archiwum Wschodnie Collection, 1945-1957; 181 prints / 4 envelopes (Box 90034 - 10.AV)
  - 96 prints depicting Poles interned in Vorkuta and other Soviet concentration camps during and after World War II, camp buildings and other facilities, and graves of those who died in the camps, 1945-1957 (Folder A-B)
  - 85 prints depicting activities of the Polish Home Army in the Wilno region during World War II, circa 1939-1944 (Folder C-D)
- Arnold, Julean Collection, 1905-1946; 96 prints / 3 envelopes (Box 73013 - 10 A-V)
  - 25 photos of maps of China, of a U.S. trade display in Shanghai, and of Julean Arnold and family (Folder A)
  - 40 photos of scenes of daily life in China, including photos and drawings of typical Chinese tools (Folder B)
  - 1 photo and 30 ink drawings of Chinese trade products (Folder C)
- Arrowsmith, Robert Collection, circa 1914-1918; circa 100 prints / 3 envelopes (Box XX135 - 10.A-V)
  - Photographs and post cards of King Albert I and Queen Elisabeth of Belgium and their children during World War I (Folder A)
  - Photographs and post cards depicting war damage and scenes at the Western front during World War I (Folder B)
- Atlantic Council of the United States Collection, 1950-1986; 97 prints / 7 envelopes (Box 82069 - 10. A-V)
  - 23 prints depicting members and officials of the Atlantic Council and their associates (Folder A)
  - 21 prints of the proceedings of the Atlantic Convention in Paris, 1962 (Folder B)
  - 18 prints of W.R. Burgess, alone and with others (Folder C)
  - 2 group photographs of members of the Atlantic Treaty Association (Box D)
  - 3 group photographs of members of the Atlantic Institute (Box E)
  - 22 prints of members of the U.S. Citizens Commission on NATO (Box F)
  - 8 photographs of unidentified individuals (Box G)
- Ausky, Stanislav A. Collection, 1945; 7 prints / 1 envelope (Box 81117 - 10.A-V Envelope A)
  Depicts General Andrei A. Vlasov and other officers and troops of the Russakaia Osvoboditel'naia Armiia.
- Babcock, Conrad Stanton Collection, 1876-1950; 13 prints, 2 negatives / 1 envelope 1 photograph album / 1 oversize box (Box XX155 - 10.A-V)
  - 1 print of C.S. Babcock; 12 prints of C.S. Babcock with others; 2 negatives (Folder A)
  - 1 photograph album of Samoa, the Philippine Islands, Yosemite National Park, California, Japan, and Vineyard Haven, Massachusetts, 1893-1904 (Folder fB)
- Bade (Wilfrid) Collection, circa 1939-1944; 10 photos / 1 envelope (Box 48019 - 8.47)
  10 photos depicting WWII Germany with special emphasis on the Hitler Youth Movement
- Bagg (Mrs. L.L.S.)Collection, circa 1917.; 143 prints / 1 envelope (Box XX163 - 8M.16)
  143 prints depicting Italy during WWI including scenes of war damage, refugees, and soldiers in the field.
- Bailey, Thomas Andrew Collection, 1915-1979; 57 slides / 2 slide boxes (Box 75003 - Slide Cabinet)
  57 slides of photographs, posters, cartoons, newspaper articles, maps, and charts used in "The Lusitania Disaster" by Thomas A. Bailey and Paul B. Ryan
- Baker, Lillian Collection, undated; 1 print (Box 87063 - oversize photo file)
  1 print depicting Manzanar Relocation Center in California during World War II
- Baker, Wilder Dupuy Collection, circa 1939-1944; 5 albums (Box 75045 - 8.24 A-C, Album fD-E)
  Albums of photographs and clippings relating to the naval career of Vice Admiral Wilder D. Baker, U.S. Navy, to U.S. Navy operations in the Pacific Theater during World War II, and to the naval base at San Diego.
- Baratov (Nikolai N.) Collection, 1914-1918; 98 prints / 3 envelopes (Box 81131 - 10.AV)
  - 36 prints depicting Russian Expeditionary Force in Persia, including groups of Kuban, Orenburg and Eiisk Cossacks. 1916-1918. 53 prints of Persia, including landscape, people and monuments. Some prints of meetings between the command of the Russian Expeditionary Force and local authorities (Folder A)
  - 9 prints, including Nicholas II, Emperor of Russia and his son; portraits of Gen. N.N. Baratov, 1914-1918 (Folder B, m*C)
- Barbour (George B.) Collection, undated; 5 photos, 27 drawings, 4 post cards / 1 envelope (Box 73071 - 10 A-V)
  5 photos, 27 drawings; and 4 post cards of scenic and cultural sites in China. Includes photo of trackers path along the Yangtze Gorgest and one photo of Barbour family members.
- Barnes (Julius H.) Collection, undated (Box XX340 - 10.A-V)
  1 photo of Julius H. Barnes, who was President of the U.S. Food Administration Grain Corporation
- Barnett, Frank R. Collection, 1957-1978; 10 prints / 1 envelope (Box 94044 - 10.A-V, Envelope A)
  10 prints of Frank R. Barnett with military and other officials at various military and military-industrial conferences.
- Barrett (Col. David D.) Collection, 48 prints plus 8 duplicates / 4 envelopes / 1 oversize box (Box 48005 - 9.15, 48005 - 10.A-V, 48005 - 8M.02)
  - 22 prints plus 8 duplicates depicting activities of the U.S. Army Observer Group in Yenan, China, 1944 (Folder A)
  - 1 photo of Armed Services attaches and officers of the Foreign Legation Guards. Peking, 1928 (Folder mB)
  - 1 photo of Yen Hsi-shan. Taipei, 1951 (Folder mC)
  - Photograph albums and parts of albums, primarily in China and Taiwan, 1944-1950 (Folder fD)
  - 1 print of David Barrett; 11 prints of David Barrett and others; 2 prints of General Douglas MacArthur; 1 print of President and Mme. Chiang Kai-Shek; 1 print of Pres, Chiang Kai-shek; 8 unidentified prints, undated (Box E)
- Barrows, Leland Collection, 9 prints / 4 folders (Box 26) (Box 97039 - 16.120)
  - 2 photographs of Phan-Tat Thanh holding a personal letter from Dwight D. Eisenhower, including one with Leland Barrows, Director, United States Operations Mission (USOM), and one showing a photograph of the President on the wall (Folder 26, 1)
  - 2 photographs of Phan-Tat-Thanh with the statuette of La Dong Tan, including one with Leland Barrows, and one of the letters from Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1955 (Folder 26, 2)
  - 1 photograph depicting the organizational structure of the U.S. Department of Agriculture for the war effort, 1942 (Folder 26, 3)
  - 9 photographs of railway tracks and trains in Cameroon (Folder 26, 4)
- Bartram, Carl Collection, 1944-1995; 11 prints / 1 envelope (Box 97008 - 10.A-V Envelope A)
  11 prints depicting United States Office of Strategic Services headquarters in England and related scenes of Anglo-American clandestine activities during World War II.
- Bastin (Catherine Sylvia) Collection, 1915-1918; 5 prints / 1 envelope (Box 62003 - 10.V)
  5 prints depicting Red Cross hospitals in France and England. C. Bastin appears in one photo.
- Battlefields, W.W. I Collection, 1918; 1 print not in an envelope (Box 44000 - 10.A-V dr.3 m)
  1 print depicting German observation posts and fortifications captured by American forces at Montfaucon.
- Bayne, Joseph Breckinridge Collection, 1919; 6 prints, 2 negatives / 2 envelopes (Box 67013 - 10.AV)
  - 1 print of Queen Marie of Romania and Dr. Bayne, and 3 prints of 1 photo of Queen Marie, signed by her and dedicated to Dr. Bayne (Folder A)
  - 1 print of Dr. Bayne, and 1 print depicting Queen Marie visiting Dr. Bayne of the American Red Cross Unit Working in the typhus epidemic district in Bucharest, Romania, May 4, 1919 (Folder mB)
- Bazily, Nikolai Collection, 260 prints/ 69 negatives/ 11 glass negatives/ 7 envelopes (Box 65017 - 10.AV)
  - 17 prints depicting N. de Basily, his colleagues, and prominent persons of Imperial Russia (Folder A)
  - 21 prints depicting Tsar Nicholas II and his family (Folder B)
  - 16 prints depicting Imperial and Soviet Russia (Folder C)
  - 1 photograph of Anna Pavlova, with a handwritten inscription to S. D. Sazonov, 1920 (Folder D)
  - 205 prints, 59 negatives, and 11 glass negatives depicting the de Basily collection of objects d'art (Folder E-G)
- Beaumont, Henry G. Collection, 1946-1948; 96 prints / 1 envelope (Box 78103-10.AV)
  Depicts defendants at the Tokyo war crime trials.
- Bell, (Lillian) Collection, circa 1914-1918; 177 slides with viewer (Box 59007 - 8.07)
  Miscellaneous collection of 177 slides with viewer pertaining to World War I (to be found in stacks)
- Bellquist, Eric Collection, 248 prints, 16 postcards / 9 envelopes (Box 881092 - 10.A-V)
  - 129 prints depicting West German Bundestag members visiting the United States, 1950 (Folder A)
  - 9 prints and 16 postcards, 1949 (Folder B)
    Includes 1 print of Elmer Davis, 1 print of Sumner Wells, 1 print of Polish farmers, and 1 print of the United States Information Service organizational chart.
  - 7 prints depicting a campaign promotion in California (Folder C)
  - 51 prints depicting Sweden, 1926-1948 (Folder D)
    Includes 9 prints of the 1948 elections, 10 prints of King Gustavus V, 9 prints of the Swedish Parliament, 9 prints of the Swedish Military, and 3 prints of political cartoons.
  - 8 prints depicting Norway (Folder E)
    Includes 1 print of King Haakon VII, and 1 print of President Carl Hambro of the Norwegian Parliament.
  - 17 prints depicting Denmark, 1920-1940 (Folder F)
    Includes 4 prints of the Danish Parliament, 3 prints of elections, 3 prints of the Danish Military, 2 prints of Foreign Minister Peter Munch, 2 prints of Prime Minister Theodore Stauning, 1 print of Nazi leader Fritz Clausen, and 1 print of commanding Officer General von Kaupisch.
  - 7 prints depicting Finland, 1930-1940 (Folder G)